<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richlitt-2015-04 on 58 Liters</title>
    <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Richlitt-2015-04 on 58 Liters</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Burnt Fen Creative LLC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apprenticeship Patterns</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/apprenticeship-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/apprenticeship-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518382/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596518382&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=burntfencreat-20&amp;linkId=aed87e63f356c9679181a650beaf1766&#34;&gt;Apprenticeship Patterns: Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=burntfencreat-20&amp;l=am2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0596518382&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt; is a gorgeous book about how to learn better, and how to place yourself in your career to be able to maximize growth through mentoring. Most code books teach you jargon - how to type this, how to say that. What they don&amp;rsquo;t teach is the rest of the trade; where to learn, how to learn better, when to position yourself. This book aims to help with that, and was one of the more instructive books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, it would have been, if I had ever finished reading it. I carried it around for months, but the mood never took me, and, at the time, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware that scheduling a reading hour and sticking to it is how to get through books like this. I eventually gave this book away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup glasses</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/backup-glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/backup-glasses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having eyes is important. When I switched to Warby Parker glasses, to get away from the square black frames I had been using to look emo for over a decade, I kept my old ones around, just in case. I normally pack them in a small bag, and keep them in a box in my luggage so that they don&amp;rsquo;t get damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup headphones</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/backup-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/backup-headphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never get caught without &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nl3fUc&#34;&gt;some cheap, good headphones&lt;/a&gt;. These don&amp;rsquo;t fit in my ears too well - they tend to come out on the slightest pressure. But they&amp;rsquo;re better than nothing, and just in case I get stuck on a long flight, I bring them with me. They don&amp;rsquo;t weigh anything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bang Bang Con shirt</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bang-bang-con-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bang-bang-con-shirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bangbangcon.com/&#34;&gt;Bang Bang Con&lt;/a&gt; is a conference in New York City every year, organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recurse.com/&#34;&gt;The Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;. My friend Rafik, who I sailed from Sicily to Malta with on my boat in 2012, gave a talk there on making a floppy disk drive play MIDI files by ejecting back and forth at a certain speed. I went along for the ride, and enjoyed the conference enough that I was glad to have the shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly like this shirt because of the color and the fit, but the ambiguous exclamation is an added plus. The !! comes from the UNIX command, and is pronounced &amp;lsquo;Bang Bang&amp;rsquo; by developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batteries</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/batteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/batteries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;../keyboard&#34;&gt;an external keyboard&lt;/a&gt; that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to plug into my computer manually. The downside of this is that I have to carry extra batteries. These weigh a lot, and I think a better, wired keyboard would be better. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a bad idea to make sure that your &lt;a href=&#34;../head-lamp&#34;&gt;headlamp&lt;/a&gt; takes the same batteries - mine take AAAs, so I failed that test here. You can shave some pounds off by making sure they are compatible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boots</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/boots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/boots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A pair of boots is the most important item you can bring with you, after a good backpack. They will get you through anything. I bought these boots, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlVcq8&#34;&gt;Lowa Renegades&lt;/a&gt;, at a hiking megastore in New York, and I&amp;rsquo;ve walked with them on four continents, over hundreds of miles, from the mid-winter wastes of Svalbard to the summer in Buenos Aires, from the jungles of Thailand to the streets of Berlin. They&amp;rsquo;re only falling apart now, three years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they finally go, I&amp;rsquo;ll but the same pair again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head lamp</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/head-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/head-lamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Always carry a headlamp.&amp;rdquo; This was my motto for years. It is less useful now than it once was, as I generally seperate out my hiking gear from my travel gear better, and as my iPhone tends to have a light on it when I need one. However, after too many times trying to maneuver through catacombs in Malta, sewers in Paris, or caves in the Adirondacks, I tend to think that carrying an extra few ounces isn&amp;rsquo;t the worst thing to do in the world. A headlamp is also incredibly helpful for late night or early morning runs; sometimes, those are the only times you can run, especially in places like Indonesia, when there are motorists everywhere during the day and it is too warm for long distances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlLCmX&#34;&gt;Black Diamond&lt;/a&gt; generally makes incredible headlamps, and you can pick them up in most places. I gave this one away to a friend by accident in Tokyo, who needed it for a late night run. I picked up another one the next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nl6o6s&#34;&gt;Apple Bluetooth Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; is pretty lightweight, and works well with a &lt;a href=&#34;../mouse&#34;&gt;wireless mouse&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlbxLJ&#34;&gt;Roost laptop stand&lt;/a&gt;, something I have now which I didn&amp;rsquo;t when I made this inventory. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a roost, you can easily prop up the keyboard using a couple of books, which is my standard strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular board is slightly bent, so I&amp;rsquo;ve had to carry around a small piece of cardboard with it to put under it to keep it from clacking. That&amp;rsquo;s annoying, no bones about it. But it works, and it keeps my wrists from killing themselves day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, if you have wrist pain, the best thing isn&amp;rsquo;t an ergonomic desk. It&amp;rsquo;s sleep. Get proper sleep at night, and I find that my wrist problems tend to fade away very fast. I learned this from the illustrious &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/louroboros&#34;&gt;@louroboros&lt;/a&gt;, who would work at weird hours but still manage to get around eight hours of sleep a night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding good painkillers can be difficult, when you need them. I always carry some backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother has a habit of taking a few of these every day, for the migraines she gets. She used to wear heavy, red lipstick, and when I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to swallow the pill alone when I was sick while traveling, I would sometimes have to use her water bottle if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything else. I&amp;rsquo;m 28, and I still connect the saccharine taste of Advil to lipstick smeared on the lip of a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve used this bottle around twice in the years I&amp;rsquo;ve carried it. During those times, I&amp;rsquo;ve been grateful for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/mouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Todd got me this mouse, when he visited family in San Diego. I could have bought one down the street in Germany without an issue, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that at the time. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to him, and I still use it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save your fingers and use a mouse. There&amp;rsquo;s a song by Sun Kil Moon about &lt;a href=&#34;http://songmeanings.com/songs/view/3530822107859473851/&#34;&gt;his friend Brett&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Brett, my friend Brett, my friend Brett, my friend Brett, he liked to play the guitar.
But he had an awkward way of playing bar chords with two fingers spreading his index and middle fingers really far apart.
One day in band practice he dropped like a deer was shot and was flipping around like a fish.
He had an aneurysm triggered by a nerve in his hand from the strain he was putting on it.
I went to see him in Ohio; he had a horseshoe shaped scar on his scalp and he talked real slow.
We played pool like we did in our teens and his head was shaved and he still wore bell-bottomed jeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;99 I was on tour in Sweden when I called home
To tell my mom I got a part in a movie when she said &amp;ldquo;Mark, there&amp;rsquo;s something that you need to know.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Brett died the other day, you really should send a letter to his mom and dad.&amp;rdquo; And I got on my train in Malmo and looked out at the snow feeling somewhere between happy and sad.
My friend Brett, my friend Brett. My friend Brett, my friend Brett. My friend Brett, my friend Brett, my friend Brett.
He had a wife and a son.
My friend Brett, my friend Brett, my friend Brett.
He just liked to play guitar and he never hurt anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is enough reason to get a mouse as anything else, really.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nalgene bottle</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/nalgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/nalgene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nqPFAh&#34;&gt;Nalgenes&lt;/a&gt; are the single greatest water bottle known to man, unless you&amp;rsquo;re interested in shaving every ounce off of your backpack, at the expense of durability. Friends of mine have shot a Nalgene multiple times with .22 caliber rifles and failed to break them, and dropped them full of ice from buildings. Some of mine - like this one - have been with me for around a dozen years. The only downside is that the opaque white ones are a bit cheaper made, and don&amp;rsquo;t hold soda or coke well without tarnishing the inside. Only store water in them, and use other liquids only for short periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good tip for nalgenes is that they can also be used to store duct tape. Simply rewrap a length around the base of the bottle, and you have both an effective insulation or heat buffer, and you have some duct tape to boot. Other than that, they work quite for stickers that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to put on your laptop. The ones on this bottle come from some LPs (&amp;ldquo;Unintelligible&amp;rdquo; was used to describe the incredible &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlJmw5&#34;&gt;World of Echo&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur Russell, while the silver circle came from, I believe, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2n7qQFT&#34;&gt;In Kind&lt;/a&gt; by Braids), from the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlQSHq&#34;&gt;Bike Snob&lt;/a&gt;, from Saarbrücken, where I spent a year and a half in Germany studying for a Masters, and from &lt;a href=&#34;https://npmjs.com&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;, who hosts code that helped make this site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wanderer bracelet</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bracelet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bracelet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I met this guy at the back of a coworking place in Bali, who looked like he had just walked off of Miami beach. The cocktail was still in his hand, and he had Boromir-length hair with a surfer&amp;rsquo;s grin on. We became friends almost instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out he had walked into the jungle and found a village of people whose only real skill was carving water buffalo bone into trinkets for tourists, which they sold for pennies. This gave Ben an idea, and a year later, he had an entire business set up, with dozens of employees, making water buffalo jewelry to sell at a markup in Long Beach and Martha&amp;rsquo;s vineyard, in the shapes of anchors, hearts, and pineapples. You can still get them; check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wandererbracelets.com/&#34;&gt;Wanderer Bracelets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben gave me this one for free. I asked for an anchor because it reminded me of my ship, Maya, which I used to sail in the Mediterranean. It&amp;rsquo;s a great reminder that there&amp;rsquo;s really opportunity almost everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>belt</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/belt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/belt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came downstairs one Christmas to the Christmas tree, a few hours early, expectant, excited. Slowly, my family trickled in, and we all sat around, opening presents. My sister&amp;rsquo;s boyfriend Brian was there, and he had a few, too. He opened one of them, from my sister, and there was this lovely floral belt, army green, that looked like it had come from a pair of cargo shorts from Old Navy. At least, I know that&amp;rsquo;s what it looked like, because it had, and it was mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to say that I was mature, and recognized that my sister may not have planned adequately for Christmas, and that she needed something special for her boyfriend. But I was 15. I stood up and demanded my belt back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to say I&amp;rsquo;ve matured and I eventually moved on to other belts. But I haven&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the same belt daily for the past dozen years. I&amp;rsquo;m wearing it right now. It&amp;rsquo;s the only belt I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really used repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to steal my belt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bike deposit</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bike-deposit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bike-deposit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Standing in the scooter rental place in Chiang Mai, my friend was adamant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, we&amp;rsquo;re not letting you get a scooter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden one before&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not the same as driving one.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I used to own ATVs and snowmobiles, I&amp;rsquo;ll be fine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s what my girlfriend said last month. Then I was holding her head, making sure her brains stayed inside, followed by weeks in the hospital and surgery. No.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left, angrily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Round the corner, I found an analog bicycle next to a few other scooters. I asked the proprietor if I could rent one. She said no problem, and gave me this receipt as a deposit. I rode my silly bike through town for the next few weeks, basket and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, I met a girl outside a cafe who said she was going into the mountains that weekend to visit an old anarchist German friend of hers, who was building his own house. I asked if I could come too. Half way there, we switched, and I finally got some experience driving in the end. Nobody died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I had dinner with my friend&amp;rsquo;s ex, miles away, on another continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve not been the same, since the accident. I forget things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely remember what my bicycle looked like, now, too. But I remember wind in my hair, coming down out of the mountains, and the long, wide Thai highway beneath me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;900 cubic centimeters  of raw whining power
No outstanding warrants for my arrest
Hi diddle dee dee
God damn
The pirates life for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ The Mountain Goats, &lt;em&gt;Jenny&lt;/em&gt;, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nlK0tu&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Hail West Texas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bintang</title>
      <link>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bintang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://58liters.com/richlitt-2015-04/bintang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sent this message to Bintang, after &lt;a href=&#34;https://theuserisdrunk.com&#34;&gt;The User is Drunk&lt;/a&gt; came out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey there, So - I made a site two weeks ago which has since gone viral, with 300,000 unique hits. It is called theuserisdrunk.com, and I offer a service where I get drunk and review people&amp;rsquo;s websites. I&amp;rsquo;ve been exclusively drinking Bintang to achieve the state of mind needed to do this service, and I realize that I have been mentioning this in each video I make and post on my website - this equates to something like 100,000 free impressions for you. I was hoping that I could contact you about some sort of sponsorship deal in the future. I would like to continue drinking Bintang, and to say that you guys are sponsoring my work. Please get in touch! thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got this response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Richard,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank you for your loyalty to our Bintang product. And it will be more appreciated if you could enjoy our product responsibly as we always encourage our consumer to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please continue to consume Bintang and spread the positive stories about Bintang.
Thank you and wish you all the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REDACTED Consumer Complaint Officer &amp;amp; CAD Divisional Secretary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__________________&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;_____________________
The information transmitted is intended only for the person or entity
to which it is addressed and may contain confidential and/or
privileged material. Any review, retransmission, dissemination or
other use of, or taking of any action in reliance upon, this information
by persons or entities other than the intended recipient is prohibited.
If you received this in error, please contact the sender and delete
the material from any computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really have nothing much more to say about Bintang.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>